If you have read well in this lesson we go
to create a student association
Hello and welcome welcome a
once again to a new lesson from this
course heading to c1 in the lesson of
Today we are going to create an association of
Spanish students and why not?
I know why the truth is I don't know why Yes
you want to participate in all of these
surveys where we choose the topic of the
lessons from the videos here
YouTube that are part of this
course heading to C1 Then subscribe to
spanish with Vicente activa las
notifications and in the tab
community I will publish every week
These surveys I remind you that the topic
This video has been chosen by everyone and
all the students of this channel So
If you want to participate, you already know what
what you have to do and I have to be
You chose the topic completely sincerely
of society and I really don't
I had no idea how to speak Spanish.
vocabulary of society had a
idea that was good could talk a little
about Marxism about Marxism talk about
proletariat capitalist class etc.
etc. But as we say in Spanish
Here everyone is from his father and his
mother and there are very different ideas so
I didn't want to create a political discussion
What I want is for you to learn
Spanish and then I had another idea that
It was about talking about a cultural festival that was
Celebrated in Teruel, it is called Las Bodas
Isabel's sure but I'd better go with this
to leave for the podcast channel Así
that if you want to learn what this is
event so traditional and so rare that
you are seeing right now in images
Subscribe to the Podcast Channel for
learn Spanish because you have it in mind
Here and well, we are now more than 6,000
listeners of this podcast so look for
podcast to learn Spanish and
subscribe so I get a better idea
We are going to create an association of
students with the rules for
this association and rights and
obligations of partners
and at the same time Well of course
We are going to learn Spanish and before
start with this lesson I'm going to send you
I'm going to give you activities for a task
so you can practice from the minute
number 1 or 2 I don't know what minute it will be
We can create an association but now
We are in the C1 rumba course. So
We will try to take our
vocabulary to the next level Why
another verb we could replace the verb
create an association for the
verb consolidate by the verb
constitute by the verb associate or by the
verb to group which of these four
options you think is the right one for you
replace the verb create Well then
stay in this lesson and pay attention
attention because if you pay attention you will
to know what the correct answer is and
Stay also in this lesson because
At the end of the video we are going to talk about
this answer and let's see what we have
learned in this lesson and that's it
I get involved, I get involved, I start talking
and I'm not done are you ready and
prepared ahead
[Music]
Well then let's start and we're going to go
to the point we need to create
our student association that
we are going to need because we are going to need
some statutes some statutes some
rules we are going to need a set of
rules we can also call it a
regulations but in this case when it is
create communities, associations or even
political parties also because we are going to
having to create statutes that are
where the rules are collected I will not
go into technical details but what
we are going to do is explain how we are going to
to form this association and also
Let's look at some rights and
obligations of the partners of this
association well then let's start with
the first free right standard
Admission to this association may
to be part of all people with the
sole objective of Well, good to learn
Spanish is supposed to be a
Spanish student association is
because all the people who form
part of this association all the
people who associate or join together
Better said so as not to sound a little
redundant to associate with this association
all the people who join this
association because we understand that they are
people who have an interest in
learn Spanish and free right of
admission because as it says in the
Article 14 of the Spanish Constitution
no type of damage will occur
discrimination based on birth
race sex religion or opinion So
We have a free right of admission
we care about none of these
features the only thing that we
will matter in this association is that
If you want to learn Spanish, rule number 2
This association is not based on a
hierarchy That is to say that there are no people who
is above the hierarchy or people who
be below the hierarchy in words
We don't care about your social class, we don't care
the same if people belong to a
upper social class or a social class
middle or lower social class gives us
Maybe the only interest we have in
This association is that you want to learn
Spanish what you have to do to join
the association is very simple there is that
fill out an admission form if
you want to join you will need
fill out this admission form
everyone has to do this
partners and all partners, everyone
we need a minimum of information and
For that, we are going to ask you to
fill out a form, okay, we need it
a little bit of information There is always a
a little bit of bureaucracy and sometimes well
Well, it will take us a little while to
read your form because as we say
Here in Spain, things go from the palace
Slow down, that's how you are Spanish, you know what
what this expression means and if you are not
is that basically all the things of
official character usually take a long time AND
Well, like this association.
We are also responsible for disseminating the
culture let's go slow with it
bureaucracy It is worth adapting to the
Spanish system is worth the good one that is
understand that it's a little bit It's a joke
following Standard all partners and the
partners undertake to respect the
regulations or well all of them
statutes of this association Well it is
understand that if you want to be part of
This association, well, you have to respect
the rules we have and the latest Rule
that we are going to take into account for
to form this association
participation and cooperation is
fundamental to form part of this
good association to join for
integrate with other students
Spanish cooperation and participation that
It's basically what I always ask you in
all the videos you participate in because
so we can see all the students
that you practice Spanish well and these are
some of the rules for establishing
This student association of
Spanish and now I'm going to ask you
Can you think of any standard that you
I would like to include in the statutes of
This association If so, if you have in
the head some Norma that you would like
include it then leave it in the comments
because as we always say
Participation and cooperation are
fundamental to integrate into this
association So as we say in
Spanish, you have to lead by example.
Okay, now let's see some
rights and obligations of all
members of this association of
number one students The Partners of
coexist and cooperate, good coexistence
not really because we are not going to live
together we are in the online world more
that living together and cooperating only cooperate
Partners shall cooperate to
learn Spanish much better this way and This
It is one of the main obligations
of the members of this association
cooperate and participate, don't forget it
the right of the partners will be assisted
Partners will assist whenever possible
but attending is not attending, it is not like going
to a place to attend an event well then
In this case in Spanish we can also
use assist someone as a
synonym of helping I remind you that this
It is the course heading to C1 we are on
a lesson from the course towards C1
then I'm going to give you little by little
the vocabulary for you to go up and up
towards C1 or up to C2 effectively
assisting someone is a way
also a little more advanced to say
help In fact if one day you have a
problem with your car on the road
Here in Spain, who do you have to call?
Well, roadside assistance that
Basically, they are the people who
They will help if you have a problem with
your car on the road assistance in
the road It's like saying help on the
road but we use the word well
following assistance which is also a
student obligation better yes
an obligation must be accepted what
want the majority man I think so
We take this as a democracy
such as when choosing the
The theme of this video we have to accept
what the majority wants we cannot
choose what a minority wants but
that we have to focus on what
want the majority No because if 80%
wants to teach a lesson about what I know
about the future and 20% want to do
a lesson about the past we have to
always think about the common good in this
majority not in the majority of students
and last Standard of rights and
student obligations
Subscribe and learn Spanish with others
channels will be considered a reason for
deception and betrayal well This is a
completely joking the truth is that
I wanted to introduce the word deception by
somewhere and betrayal not to deceive and
betray wanted to introduce these
words but I couldn't find a context
suitable for introducing them so
I hope you don't get angry, learn Spanish
with whoever you want, with whoever you like the most
like it well because I think that
We have already established all the statutes
not all the rules of this
association So I think we're already there
prepared to form our
Spanish student association yes
You have any other Standard that you
I would like to include Don't forget Well that
leave it in the comments, well yes
you want to continue learning Spanish and
taking your level of Spanish up to the
level c1 because I want you to know that in the
online Spanish academy in particular
on the course heading to C1 we are
working with all this vocabulary that
you have learned so far and also with
the one in this lesson as you can see here
with another explanatory video and with
activities to expand your vocabulary
and get to c1 well and at the beginning of
This lesson, then I asked you which one
Do you think it would be the appropriate verb for
replace to create an association you have
given to choose between four verbs
different As for example consolidate
to constitute, associate or group together
association And if you have paid attention to
This lesson Well, you already know what it is
answer effectively
to form an association we use
constitute when we create a set of
rules of norms etcetera etcetera or a
set of things to create something by
example we can constitute a
association we can form an
community we can also constitute A
government can also be formed
assembly to talk, dialogue and negotiate
common points once again you can say
perfectly create an association or
You can also use another verb that
It's like founding an association but I
Little by little in this course I am giving you
a vocabulary that will increasingly help you
Well, well, then get to the
level that you want to be at AND
If with this lesson you have learned
words such as majority
minority hierarchy constitute a
association etc. etc. as
We say in Spanish I can give myself with
a song in the teeth that basically
It means that I feel satisfied
if you have learned all these words
And well that's all for this lesson.
Once again, thank you very much for learning.
Spanish and see you next time
lesson see you later
[Music]